Akshat Surolia

24, Nazar Bagh, Ratlam, Madhya Pradesh, 457001, India

🖪 +91 808-578-4715 | 🗬 akshatsurolia0@gmail.com | 🗘 AsianZeus | in akshatsurolia

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

A diligent Data Scientist with 2 years of experience who takes pride in building models that translate data points into business. Strong willingness to exhibit my proficiency in Machine Learning, Statistics and Computing Methodologies in the professional environment. Specialized in Python, Hands on experience in the domain of Computer Vision and Natural Language Processing.

SKILLS

Python

Java

Flask

Dialogflow

Exploratory Data Analysis

Natural Language Processing

SQL

JavaScript

TensorFlow

Machine Learning

Image Processing

AWS

• C++

Git

PyTorch

Deep Learning

Computer Vision

GCP

EXPERIENCE

Associate Data Scientist DSMATICS | Pune, India

Aug 2021 - Current

- Designed, Developed and Deployed a Recommendation System to understand Human Persona and predict Personality Scores via Automated Question Generation based on Deep Natural Language Understanding and Natural Language Generation using State of the Art Transformers and advanced ML and NLP techniques.
- Designed, Implemented and Deployed a whole pipeline to generate random faces and edit with total of 50 local and global facial features via Latent Space Exploration and Disentanglement via StyleGAN, StyleGAN2, Vision Transformers, VGG, ResNet, ModNET with Background Removal and Face Swap.
- Developed advanced mathematical and statistical techniques to predict business outcomes.
- Helped stakeholders meet needs and resolve problems by recommending data-driven solutions.
- Build APIs for chat-bots from scratch with intent classisfication.
- Designed and deployed machine learning solutions to enhance data analysis work.

Computer Vision Engineer

Necesario Innovations | IIT Gandhinagar, India

Jan 2021 - Jul 2021

- Lead Programmer and Technical Head of the product 'Snapper'.
- Implemented real-time HDR on Jetson Nano and applied Contrast Enhancement.
- Developed and Optimized models for 3D model Reconstruction, 3D Photography, Super Resolution, and Image Enhancement by applying 8-Bit Quantization, and using EfficientNetV2 feature maps to increase the model efficiency by 40% and making the inference 5 times faster.

- Led the team of 11 members to develop a complete chat-bot with Dialogflow as a web extension to serve tech and programming queries with concise answers up to 100 words and articles cards.
- Supervised the team, designed the pipeline and developed a webhook to construct a query-based extractive summarization probabilistic model, achieving 94.2% accuracy.

Research Project Under HOD Supervision Gujarat University | Ahmedabad, India

Jul 2020 - Dec 2020

- Created an application to generate handwritten text with an approach of image to image translation using Cycle Generative Adversarial Networks (CycleGAN).
- Implemented in python and TensorFlow framework, deployed on Heroku.

Research Project in collaboration with IIT Bombay Gujarat University | Ahmedabad, India

Jan 2020 - Jun 2020

- Engineered a handwritten text recognition system to digitize prescription images achieving 74% accuracy on the test set.
- Redesigned the model architecture with CNN, BiRNN, and Seq2Seq with python and TensorFlow, Image processing, and segmentation by OpenCV.

EDUCATION

M.Sc. in Artificial Intelligence & Machine Learning

June 2021

Department of Computer Science, Gujarat Univeristy, Ahmedabad, India

Graduated with 8.3 CGPA.

Bachelors in Computer Applications

Faculty of Computer Applications and Information Technology, GLS University, Ahmedabad, India

May 2019

- Graduated with 9.07 CGPA.
- Awarded Best Student of Batch by GLS University.
- Attained 1st position in Smart Gujarat Hackathon in Health and Family Welfare Department.
- Won Relay Programming (Java), in a National Level Tech-Fest event.
- Secured 1st position in Extempore, in a National Level Tech-Fest event.

Higher Secondary Certificate – 12th

St. Joseph's Convent Sr. Sec. School, Ratlam, India

May 2016

Graduated with 9.4 CGPA

CERTIFICATIONS

Generative Adversarial Networks (GANs) Specialization
Data Engineering with Google Cloud Specialization
TensorFlow Developer Specialization
Deep Learning Specialization
Machine Learning
Intermediate Python
deeplearning.ai
deeplearning.ai
Stanford University
Data Camp